Chef John's Italian Meatballs. 135 min · 10 servings · Italian
Ingredients: 15. 1/3 cup plain bread crumbs; 1/2 cup milk or beef broth; 2 tablespoons olive oil; 1 onion, diced
Step 1. Cover a baking sheet with foil and spray lightly with cooking spray. Soak bread crumbs in milk in a small bowl for 20 minutes.
Step 2. Heat olive oil in a skillet over medium heat. Cook and stir onion until onion has softened and is translucent, about 5 minutes. Reduce heat to low an…
Step 3. Gently stir beef and pork together in a large bowl. Add onions, bread crumb mixture, eggs, ricotta cheese, Parmesan cheese, parsley, garlic, salt, bl…
Step 4. Preheat the oven to 425°F (220°C).
Step 5. Form mixture into balls about 1 1/2 inches in diameter. Arrange in a single layer on the prepared baking sheet.
Step 6. Bake in the preheated oven until browned and cooked through, 15 to 20 minutes.
Step 7. Serve with your favorite tomato sauce. Tip: After baking, add meatballs to tomato sauce and simmer 1 to 2 hours for best flavor.
You're ready. Use Make It for checkboxes on the page.